# Temi Kelani

**AWS ARCHITECT** 

temikelani@icloud.com, +1 (646) 854-5958

A Cloud Architect with 3+ years experience architecting, designing, and implementing effective and performant AWS solutions, who enjoys working with companies to build the most cost-effective and efficient infrastructure for their business needs - using only the tools they need.

#### CONTACT

#### **Email**

**LinkedIn** 

#### **GitHub**

+1 (646) 854-5958

Remote - Anywhere in The World

#### **CERTIFICATES**

**AWS Associate Solutions Architect** 

#### **PROJECTS**

**Project Portfolio** 

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **BENG ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING**

Glasgow Caledonian University United Kingdom 2015

### **TECH STACK**

Languages: Python, Bash, JavaScript

OS: Linux

IAC: CloudFormation, Terraform, Ansible

CI/CD: GitHub Actions, Circle-CI

AWS: EC2, Lambda, Auto Scaling, ELB,

EBS, S3, VPC, DynamoDB, RDS, SNS,

SQS, Event Bridge, CloudFront,

CloudWatch, CloudTrail, Config, SSM,

IAM, KMS CLI, Route 53, Backup, CDK

Jira, Agile, Git

**In Training:** EKS, Docker, Kubernetes, Prometheus,

# CAREER HIGLIGHTS

- Led the design and implementation of an automated disaster recovery solution leveraging Lambda, AWS backup service, and AWS Databases to protect business critical information and processes
- Implementation of automation solutions utilizing lambda to relieve burden
  of manual tasks allowing the reallocation of company resources to focus on business
  critical issues.
- Infrastructure security management through (mention IAM and KMS solutions)resulting in greater access management and protection of PII.

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## AWS Consultant | Upwork | 2020 - Present

Producing custom AWS Lambda scripts for:

- Resource management: Identifying and deleting unused resources,
- User permissions and management: Adding/Removing users from groups, creating/deleting users, rotating access keys
- Filtering resources: Based on custom criteria (tags, SSM, AMI id, region, date/time)
- Automating resource and DR backups (EC2, S3, DynamoDB, RDS, EBS): On-demand, scheduled or event triggered using DynamoDB, AWS Lambda, Event Bridge Rules, AWS Backup etc.
- CRUD/Cron web scraping Jobs and S3 data dumps

Custom configuration (CloudFormation/Terraform) templates for a range of solutions including:

- Monitoring and alerts via SNS, Cloud Watch, and AWS Lambda
- Configuring multi-AZ/region fault tolerant solutions architecture
- Deploying highly available web applications with EC2, VPC, Lambda, CloudFront, API Gateway

# Training Cloud Architect | Per Scholas | 2020 - 2021

Per Scholas is an AWS re/Start company that provides real-world, scenario-based learning, labs, and coursework

- Voted team lead for 3 consecutive sprints
- Built, maintained, and automated the provisioning of cloud infrastructure utilizing CloudFormation, terraform, Ansible and CICD with GitHub Actions and AWS CodeBuild Suite
- Leveraged AWS cloud services, including EC2, ELB, ASG, and S3, to build and secure scalable and flexible systems designed to handle expected and unexpected load bursts.
- Created, onboarded, and managed users, permissions, directories, and files in Linux environment
- Provided security compliance through automated programmatic remediation using Config, SSM and Lambda.
- Conceived, developed, and configured network infrastructure within VPC with public and private subnets, configured routing tables, security groups, and internet gateway.
- Defined and implemented monitoring metrics and logging systems using CloudWatch, Config, and CloudTrail and executed Python script utilizing Cron.

#### Data Analyst Intern | Hudson Meridian | 2018 - 2020

- Responsible for maintaining excluded worker status during the Covid-19 pandemic with data and dashboards resulting in 99% uptime and continued compliance with New York Department of Buildings Regulations
- · Reproducing data collection and procedures at multiple job sites
- Designed and maintained data ingestion pipelines freeing up 40% of the workday
- Monitoring inventory and generated alerts based on volume and for upcoming events
- Maintained database of employees, inventory, and incidents.